roguefcu.org 2010-06-13

# Rogue FCU | Privacy Policy Disclosure

### Our Privacy Pledge

At Rogue Federal Credit Union we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by Rogue Federal Credit Union and our affiliate, Rogue Federal Credit Union Investment and Insurance Services. This notice explains what types of member information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it. 

### Member Information We Collect

The Credit Union collects only relevant information about members that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you (member information) which is "nonpublic." The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources: 

_Application Information._ We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide to us or our affiliate for membership, deposit account, EFT services, loans, financial planning, securities brokerage, insurance, or other Credit Union services. This information includes: name, address, e-mail address, social security number, birth date, phone number, employment and financial status, and credit history. 

_Your Transactions._ Any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, transactions through Internet Banking, over the phone or at a branch we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, the date, amount, location of the transaction, and other pertinent information. Our affiliate may also provide us with reports on your securities and insurance transactions. 

_Credit Reports._ When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests. 

_Online._ We may obtain information you provide online when you visit our website, www.roguefcu.org. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, Internet Banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail. 

_Copyrights._ You should assume that everything on the Rogue Federal Credit Union site is copyrighted unless otherwise noted and that it must not be used except as provided with the express written consent of RFCU. Images of people, places, or other images displayed on the RFCU site are either the property of, or used with permission by, RFCU. Use of these images by you or other third parties is prohibited unless expressly permitted. Any unauthorized use of these images may violate copyright laws, trademark laws, the laws of privacy and publicity, and other applicable regulations and statutes. 

Rogue Federal Credit Union has not reviewed all of the sites which are linked to the Rogue Federal site, and the fact of such links does not indicate any approval or endorsement of any material contained on any linked site; your connection to any such linked site is at your own risk. 

### Member Information We Share

In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliate and third party service providers. However, we only share information to the extent necessary to service your account or offer new services to you. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is generally only shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law. 

_Sharing Information with Credit Union Affiliates._ Our wholly-owned affiliate, Rogue Federal Member Financial Services, LLC, provides insurance products and services. We may share personal information (such as name, address, and account number) and account information (such as type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history) with our affiliate so they can serve you more efficiently. Our affiliate maintains the same privacy standards as the Credit Union. 

_Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers._ In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including: data processing companies, check, ATM and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, insurance companies, collection agencies, credit reporting agencies, financial planners, securities brokerage, and insurance companies, and financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information to third party service providers depending on the specific services provided: 

  * Personal information (name, address, and account number)
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history)
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations, and type of transaction)

We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of our affiliate or other financial service providers, we control the member information used to make such offers. 

_Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted._ We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate. 

### Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards

We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees have access to such member information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees has regular access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future. 

### Online Privacy Protections

At our website, [www.roguefcu.org](http://www.roguefcu.org/), you may (when activated) apply for accounts and services and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. The application information we accept online and our Internet Banking service relies on industry standard "Secure Sockets Layer" (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. Generally, our e-mails are not secure. However, if we ask you to e-mail us information other than your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, it will be obtained using a secure (SSL encryption) e-mail form. When you visit our website, you can access site information, without revealing your personal identity. In the future, we may use a "cookie" in order to help us identify you and to track your website visit. A "cookie" is a piece of information that our web server may store on your computer hard drive and retrieve later. The cookie would not request, require or collect any personal identity information and you remain anonymous. Your member information would not be accessed by or stored within a cookie in any way. 

### Protecting Children’s Information Privacy

Our online financial services are not designed for or directed toward children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents. 

### Privacy Policy Inquiries

If you have any questions about our privacy practices contact us by calling (541) 858-7328, 1 (800) 856-7328 or writing to us at Rogue Federal Credit Union, 1370 Center Drive, Medford, Oregon 97501. 

June 2007
